Rui Dantas

Full-Stack Developer

- 6472378213
- Toronto, Ontario
- **▼** Portfolio
- in LinkedIn
- Github

PROFILE

Full-stack web developer with a passion for Front-end Development. With my extensive background as a self-taught freelance Creative Director, Photographer/Videographer, and Graphic Designer, I have honed my work ethic, problem-solving expertise and collaborative skills, consistently delivering exceptional results that leave happy and satisifed clients. Through a strong process of comprehensive research, meticulous planning, innovative design, efficient development, and rigorous testing. I possess the expertise to create fully functional web applications tailored to meet the unique requirements of clients.

SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS, SASS, SQL, EJS, TypeScript

Framework & Libraries: NodeJS, React, Axios/Ajax, Express, EJS, jQuery, NextJS, Tailwind CSS

Systems & Database: PostgreSQL, Prisma, Git, GitHub, Command Line

Testing: Jest, Mocha, Chai, Storybook, Cypress **Software:** Photoshop, Lightroom, After Effects, Premier Pro, Figma, Blender

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Labs

10/2022 – 05/2023 Diploma Full-Stack Web Development

Chamiande College School

09/2012 – 06/2016 High School Diploma

PROJECTS

Pomodoro Timer App 🖸

Front-end

10/2023

Pomodoro Study timer

Front-end: React, Tailwind CSS

MovieHub ☑

Full-Stack

11/2023 - In Progress

A movie & TV show tracker. Leave reviews and ratings on TV shows & movies, check what platform they are being streamed on

Front-end: NextJS, JavaScript, SASS, Axios **Back-end:** NodeJS, Express.js, Postgres & Prisma

Scheduler 🛮

Front-end

03/2023 - 04/2023

Interview Scheduler is a single-page application (SPA) using React that allows users to book technical interviews between students and mentors.

Front-end: ReactJS, SCSS, Axios

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Photographer/Videographer

Freelance

09/2016 – present | Toronto, Canada

- Capture and edit visual content: Capture and edit visual content, including photos, videos, and graphics, for use in various mediums such as websites, social media, and marketing materials.
- Collaborate with clients: Collaborate with clients to understand their vision and goals, and then develop a strategy for capturing and creating
- Design and produce marketing materials: I was also
 responsible for designing and producing marketing materials,
 such press kits, and other promotional materials. This includes
 selecting and editing visual content, as well as creating layout
 and design elements that effectively convey the client's
 message and brand identity.

Electrician

Riverline Group Inc.

02/2018 – 01/2023 | Toronto, Canada

- **Strong Problem-Solving Abilities**: honed my problem-solving skills, enabling me to identify and resolve complex electrical issues efficiently.
- Attention to Detail: developed a keen eye for detail, ensuring the precision and safety of electrical installations.
- Communication and Collaboration: collaborated with diverse teams and communicated effectively with clients to ensure projects met their requirements.